{
  "reference_number": "1773",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "This question is loaded!. Where is the option to select...\"no target\"?? Setting any target for carbon dioxide emission reduction is futile\n\n as it will have no effect of world climate and cost ratepayers for no benefit"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "again this question is loaded and will not provide a balances answer!. Whoever prepared this questionnaire has obviously already\n decided the outcome and is just presenting question to support it.. There is no scientific data to support man made climate change,\n\n and the benefits of increased levels of carbon dioxide far outweigh the adverse impacts, yet all the bias research is focused on the\n adverse impacts with no recognition of the benefits"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "it shouldnt be setting a target"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "What sane person would set a target that cannot be reviews if circumstances change. That is just plain dumb..Only the Greens who\n\n do not consider individual citizens financial situation would put our country in such a stupid legal position"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "only if these budgets recognize the true cost of this flawed policy on climate change"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - each incoming Government should have the option to review the third budget in the sequence",
      "answer_index": 14,
      "notes": "for gods sake, a budget is just a best guess at the time it is made. Government MUST be able to review as circumstances change"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "set back and take a real hard look at the bullshit propaganda around the supposed climate change. Global temperatures are falling\nnot rising. there is significantly greater benefits in higher levels of carbon dioxide, than lower yet all the recent \"climate change\"\n\nresearch has been bias on the adverse impact with no consideration of hte benefits."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Advising the Government on policy settings in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 6,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "the committee makeup MUST include experts whos position holds that climate change is not man made as the \"science is NOT\nsettled\" and there are many experts who do not agree with the current fashionable mantra that climate change is man made"
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "For f..ks sake, the whole point of this bill is for our Government to put in place measures to manage the supposed man made climate\nchange. This question is pointless!"
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "page 47 does not list any \"functions\" so have no idea what this question relates to"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "This form is a loaded questionnaire and does not represent a submission that represents my personal view. It presents questions\nthat support a pre-determined outcome and should not be used as evidence of consultation and the publics collective position on\n\nthis bill"
    }
  ]
}
